Inventory of the Iranian Political Opposition Literature collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Jabhah-'i Najat-i Īrān, 1981-1985; 39-42 (Box 39-42: 1)
  - Serials (Folder 39-41)
    - Nāmeh-yi Jabhah-'i Najat-i Īrān, (Copenhagen, Denmark: s.n.), newsletters, 1361-1364 (1982-1985) (Folder 39)
      - Shumārah-i 7-9, 11-20, 22-27, 29-30, 33, 35, 37, 41-42, 44-45, 1361 Āzar 5-1362 Ābān 30, (1982 November 26-1983 November 21) (Folder 39: 11-13)
      - Shumārah-i 16-26, 1363 Mehr-1364 Khordād (1984 September-1985 May) (Folder 39: 14)
      - Dawreh-yi jadīd, shumārah-i 4-7, 9, 11-15, 19, 21-23, 27-31, 1364 Ordibihisht 24-Āzar 12 (1985 May 14-December 3) (Folder 39: 15-16)
    - Payk-i Najat, (Copenhagen, Denmark: Jabhah), journals, 1363 (1984-1985) (Folder 40-42)
      - Shumārah-i 133-182, 1363 Mordād 24-Mehr 18 (1984 August 15-October 11) (Folder 40: 1-10)
      - Shumārah-i 183-256, 1363 Mehr 20-Day 18 (1984 October 12-1985 January 8) (Folder 41: 1-11)
      - Shumārah-i 257-307, 1363 Day 21-Esfand 21 (1985 January 11-March 12) (Folder 42: 1-4)
  - General newsletters and clippings, 1361-1363 (1982-1984) (Folder 42: 5)
- Kunfidirāsyun-i Jahānī Dānish'āmuzān va Dānishjuyān-i Īrān (Ittihād-i Millī), 1965-1985, undated; 42-48 (Box 42-48: 5)
  Also includes printed matter published by the Iranian Student Association in the United States (ISAUS) and Kunfidirāsīyun-i Jahānī Muhāsalīn va Dānishjuyān-i Īrānī
  Arranged in three groups: Serials, Monographs, booklets, and pamphlets, and General
  - Serials (Folder 42-46)
    - Avval-i Ordibihisht, shumārah-i 1 va 6, (Karlsruhe, West Germany: I.S.V.), newsletter and booklet, 1359 Mordād va 1360 Tīr (1980 July and 1981 June) (Folder 42: 6)
    - Bulitan-i khabarī, shumārah-i 2, newspaper, 1357 Mehr (1978) (Folder 42: 7)
    - Bulitan-i kunfidirāsīyun, (Frankfurt: CISNU), booklets, 1350-1352 Mordād (1971-1973 July) (Folder 42: 8-9)
    - Dānishjoo, quarterly review of the ISAUS, (Berkeley, Calif.: ISAUS), journals, newspaper, and magazine, 1353-1359 (1974-1980) (Folder 42-43)
      - Dawreh-yi 22, shumārah-i 3-4, 1353 Esfand-Khordād (1974 February-June) (Folder 42: 10)
      - Dawreh-yi 23, shumārah-i 1 va 4, 1353 Āban-1354 Mordād (1974 October-1975 August) (Folder 42: 11-12)
      - Dawreh-yi 24, shumārah-i 1-4, 1354 Day-1355 Mordād (1976 January-July) (Folder 42: 13-15)
      - Dawreh-yi 25, shumārah-i 1, 1355 Āzar (1976 November) (Folder 43: 1)
      - Dawreh-yi 26, shumārah-i 1, 1356 Bahman (1978 February) (Folder 43: 2)
      - Shumārah-i 6, newspaper, 1980 March (Folder 43: 3)
    - Farhang-i khalq, Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Irān dar Pāris, shumārah-i 2, (Paris: UEIF), journal, 1357 Mehr (1978 September) (Folder 43: 4)
    - Iran Report (German), (Frankfurt: CISNU), journal, 1973 December (Folder 43: 5)
    - Iran Report (English), no.2, (Berkeley, Calif.: ISAUS), journal, 1974 June (Folder 43: 6)
      Includes a feature on the Iranian People's Movement 1953-1973
    - "Māhnāmeh-yi I.S.U.", Iranian Student Union, West Virginia Tech, sāl-i avval, shumārah-i 1, newsletter, 1976 July (Folder 43: 7)
    - Nāmeh Pārsi, urgān-i tahqīqī-i kunfidirāsīyun-i jahānī muhāsalīn va dānishjuyān-i īrānī, (Berlin: CISNU), journals, 1345-1357 (1966-1978) (Folder 43-44)
      - Sāl-i 5?, shumārah-i 6 and unnumbered, 1345 Ābān-Bahman (1966 January-October) (Folder 43: 8-9)
      - Sāl-i 7, shumārah-i 3, 1347 Day (1968 December) (Folder 43: 10)
      - Sāl-i 8, shumārah-i 1-2, 1348 Khordād-Mehr (1969 May-September) (Folder 43: 11)
      - Sāl-i 11, shumārah-i 2-3, 1351 Ābān-Āzar (1972 October-November) (Folder 43: 12-13)
      - Sāl-i 12, shumārah-i 1-4, 1352 Farvardin-Āzar (1973 March-November) (Folder 43: 14-15)
      - Sāl-i 13?, shumārah-i 1, 1353 (1974) (Folder 44: 1)
      - Sāl-i 14, shumārah-i 1-2, 1355 (1976) (Folder 44: 2)
      - Sāl-i 15, zamimeh, 1367 (1978) (Folder 44: 3)
    - Nāmeh-yi sīyāsī, Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Īrānī dar Amrikā, shumārah-i 4-6, newsletters, 1361 (1982) (Folder 44: 4)
      Includes some articles written in English
    - Payām-i āzādī, shumārah-i 3, newspaper, 1358 Day (1979 December) (Folder 44: 5)
    - Payām-i Dānishjoo, (Austin, Tex.: s.n.), journals, 1354-1358 (1975-1979) (Folder 44-45)
      - Sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 4 va sāl-i 2, shumārah-i 1-2, (Austin, Tex.: s.n.), 1354-1355 (1975-1976) (Folder 44: 6-7)
        These two journals are also duplicated in the bound volumes of Payām-i Dānishjoo. See also Box 45, Items 1-2
      - Sāl-i 1-2, shumārah-i 1-15, (Austin, Tex.: s.n.), bound volumes of journals, 1353-1357 (1974-1978) (Folder 45: 1-2)
        Includes some duplicates of issues in Box 44, Folders 6-7
      - Dawreh-yi 2, shumārah-i 6-9 va dawreh-yi 3, shumārah-i 1-7, bound volume of journals, 1357-1358 (1978-1979) (Folder 45: 3)
        Journals within volume are not in order
    - Payām-i Dānishjoo, (Brooklyn, N.Y.: s.n.), magazines, 1355-1357 (1976-1978) (Folder 44)
      - Sāl-i 3, shumārah-2 va sāl-i 4, shumārah-i 1-2, 1355-1356 Khordād (1976-1977 May) (Folder 44: 8)
      - Dawreh-yi 2, shumārah-i 2-5 va makhsus, 1356 Shahrivar-1357 Farvardīn (1977 August-1978 March) (Folder 44: 9-10)
    - Payk, publication of Iranian students at the University of California, Berkeley, sāl-i 8, shumārah-i 1, newsletter, 1365 (1986) (Folder 44: 11)
    - Paymān, neshrī-yi hay'at-i dafā'ī-i CISNU, newsletters, 1344-1357 (1965-1978) (Folder 44: 12-13)
    - Pazhvak, shumārah-i 9, 1356 Āzar (1977 November) (Folder 44: 14)
    - "Political Repression in Iran," (Berkeley, Calif: ISAUS), journal, 1971 March and October (Folder 44: 15)
    - Razm-i dānishjoo, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 2 va sāl-i 2, shumārah-i 1, (Houston, Tex.: ISAUS), 1355 Mordād-Ābān (1976 July-October) (Folder 46: 1)
    - Resistance, publication of ISAUS, vol. 5 nos. 1, 7, and special issue; vol. 6, no. 1, newspapers and newsletter, 1977 November-1979 January (Folder 46: 2)
      See also Box 47, Folder 8 and Box 48, Folder 6 for supplemental serial monographs
    - Sattar khan Bairagi, no. 14, newspaper, 1357 Mordād (1978 August) (Folder 46: 3)
      In Azerbaijani
    - Sepher, shumārah-4 va fuq ilādeh, journals, 1355 Ordibihisht va 1356 Shahrivar (1976 April and 1977 September) (Folder 46: 4)
    - Sīyāhkal, (Berkeley, Calif.: ISAUS), journal, 1355 (1976) (Folder 46: 5)
    - Shānzdahomeh Āzar, monthly bulletin of CISNU, (Hannover: s.n.), newspapers and newsletters, 1355-1362 (1976-1983) (Folder 46: 6-18)
    - Women and Struggle in Iran, Committee for Women's Democratic Rights in Iran, nos. 3-4, (Glendale, Calif.: WC-ISA), magazine and newsletter, 1984 Summer-1985 Spring (Folder 46: 19)
    - Assorted newsletters, 1355-1261 (1976-1982) (Folder 46: 20)
  - Monographs and booklets (Folder 47-48)
    - An Alliance of Reactions and Terror: the revealing story of nearly 15 years of anti-Iranian activities abroad, (Tehran: Focus Publications), booklet, 1977 February (Folder 47: 1)
    - Asnādī dar bāreh-yi mobārzāh bar 'alih pulīs-i sīyāsī, Sāzmān-i dānishjuyān-i īrānī dar amrikā, booklet, probably 1976 (Folder 47: 2)
    - Asrār-i fa'ālīat'hāi zadd īrānī dar khārij az kishvar: gozāreshī kutāh az 10 sāl talāsh dushman-i irān va guruh'hāi mukhtalifī keh bivujud āvardan, booklets, circa 1355 (1976) (Folder 47: 3)
    - Dar bāreh-yi Sāvāk, (Frankfurt: CISNU), monograph, 1348 Āzar (1969 December) (Folder 47: 4)
    - Gozārash-i khānum La Fou-Viron hiquqdan-i Farānsavī az mashahadat khod dar īrān, (Frankfurt: CISNU), monograph, 1978 January (Folder 47: 5)
    - Gushi'hāi az khārat-i khalq-i īran, (Frankfurt: Intishārat-i Da'reh-i Farhangī), booklet, 1352 (1973) (Folder 47: 6)
    - Iftikhār bar afsarān-i shahīd Tudah-āi, ISAUS, 1355 Ābān (1976 October) (Folder 47: 7)
    - Imperialist Disguises and Liberal Illusions (1900-1963), no. 1, (Berkeley, Calif.: ISA), serial monograph, 1978 December (Folder 47: 8)
      Supplement to Resistance. See also Box 48, folder 6
    - In Solidarity with the Iranian Revolutionary Movement, Iranian Student Association in Sacramento, booklet, 1976 August (Folder 47: 9)
    - Inqilāb dar Omān, (College Park, Md.: ISAUS), booklet, 1975 December (Folder 47: 10)
    - Iran: 50 ans de crimes des Pahlavi, 50 ans de lutte du peuple, (Paris: UEIF), booklet, 1977 February (Folder 47: 11)
    - Javdaneh-yi mardī az Vīetnām, (S.l.: Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Īrānī dar Shīkāgu (Chicago), monograph, undated (Folder 47: 12)
    - Junbish-i dānishjuyān-i īrān va vazāyif-i usulī-i ān, Sāzmān-i Chirik'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān, monograph, 1354 Ordibihisht (1975 April) (Folder 47: 13)
    - "Khosrow Ruzbeh", (Berkeley, Calif.: Intishārat-i anjumān-i dānishjuyān-i īrān dar dānishgāh-i kālifurniā), pamphlet, 1346 (1967) (Folder 47: 14)
    - Majmu'āh-yi az āsar, Khosrow Golsorkhi (Frankfurt: Intishārat-i CISNU), monograph, 1353 Khordād (1974 July) (Folder 47: 15)
    - Mārksism cheh mī guyand?, Hossein Shih 'Aliah and Mahsoud Shih 'Aliah, booklets, circa 1980 (Folder 47: 16)
    - Masā'il-i īrān dar matbu'at-i jahān, (Frankfurt: CISNU), monograph, 1350 (1971) (Folder 47: 17)
      Includes clippings from international newspapers about the political climate in Iran
    - Masā'il-i īrān dar sāl-i gozashteh, vīzhehnāmeh-yi noruz, (College Park, Md.: ISAUS), booklet, undated (Folder 47: 18)
    - Mukhtasarī dar bāreh-yi adabiyat mu'asar-i īrān, shumārah-i 1, (Köln, West Germany: CIS), booklet, circa 1970s (Folder 47: 19)
    - Nāmeh-yi sar goshādeh beh hi'yat-i dabīrān-i Kunfidirāsīyun-i Jāhānī, Mujāhidīn-i Khalq, monograph, circa 1360s (1980s) (Folder 48: 1)
    - Nīkaragu'ā, (S.l.: ISAUS, Left Platform), booklet, late 1970s (Folder 48: 2)
      Translations of speeches and writings by Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional (FSLN), in Persian.
    - "No Honorary Degree to Ashraf, Down With the Shah", (College Park, Md.: ISAUS), photocopy, 1976 (Folder 48: 3)
      Compilation of newsletters, clippings, and letters circulated by ISAUS regarding Ashraf Pahlavi's graduation from John Hopkin's University in 1976
    - Payām-i Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān beh Dānishāmuzān-i mīhān porsat-i īrān, booklet, undated (Folder 48: 4)
    - Pīrāmun-i Rivīzīunīsm (Mārksist-Lininist), booklets, circa 1350s (1970s) (Folder 48: 5)
    - Shah's Inferno: Abadan, no. 2, (Berkeley, Calif.: ISA), serial monograph, 1978 August 19 (Folder 48: 6)
      Supplement to Resistance. See also Box 47, folder 8
    - Tahlīlī-i ijmalī az uzāh'i iqtisādī-sīyāsī-i jam'āh-yi īrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Īrānī dar Pārīs), monograph, 1357 (1978) (Folder 48: 7)
    - "Taskhīr sefārat" va muzuh' Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān", report, undated (Folder 48: 8)
    - Yādnāmeh-yi razmandigān-i shahīd Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-i Fadā'ī-i Khalq, Kunifidirāsīyun-i Jahāni Muhasālīn va Dānishjuyān-i Īrān, booklet, 1353 (1974) (Folder 48: 9)
  - General (Folder 48)
    - Administrative, booklets, 1346-1369 (1957-1990) (Folder 48: 10)
      Includes consititution and reports from congress meetings.
    - Defense testimonies and other legal matter, booklets, 1347-1355 (1968-1976) (Folder 48: 11)
      Includes some English translations
    - Flyers, circa 1970s (Folder 48: 12)
      Includes flyers promoting ISAUS discussion forums and other events as well as a flyer protesting the Shah's 2500 year celebration in 1971
    - Reports, 1350-1361 (1971-1982) (Folder 48: 13-14)
      Includes a report to the United States Congress written by ISAUS on the violation of human rights in Iran (in English)
    - Other booklets, 1970-1976, undated (Folder 48: 15)
- Nahzat-i Āzādi-i Irān, 1976-1989; 49-50 (Box 49-50: 15)
  Arranged in two groups: Serials and Monographs, booklets, and pamphlets
  - Serials (Folder 49)
    - Maktab, shumārah-i 1-8, (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), journals, 1365 Ābān-1366 Mordād (1986 November-1987 August) (Folder 49: 1-2)
    - Payk-i Nahzat, shumārah-i 20-23, 27-28, 32-34, (Tehran: Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān), journals and photocopies, 1362-1363 (1983-1984) (Folder 49: 3-5)
    - Newsletters and press releases, 1360-1368 (1981-1989) (Folder 49: 6-7)
      Press release in English
  - Monographs, booklets, and pamphlets (Folder 49-50)
    - Asnād-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān, jild-i avval, qissmat-i sivvum, (Springfield, Mont.: Intishārat-i Asnād-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān Khārij az Kishvar), booklet, 1355 Tīr (1976 June) (Folder 49: 8)
    - Bahtar mobārzeh kunīm, (Bellville, Ill.: Intishārat-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, 1355 Day (1976 December) (Folder 49: 9)
    - Bīyād hamāseh āfarīnān davāzdahom-i mahram, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Davāzdahom-i Mahram), monograph, 1356 (1977) (Folder 49: 10)
    - Dar bāreh-yi qyām-i hamāseh āfarinān: qām va tabrīz, jīld-i 2, chāp-i 1, (Bellville, Ill.: Intishārat-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān Khārij az Kishvar), booklet, 1357 Farvardīn (1978 March) (Folder 49: 11)
    - Khodā va insān; Khodā dar ijtemā', Mohandes Mehdi Bazargan, (Houston, Tex.: Book Distribtion Center), chāp-i avval, booklets, 1355 Tīr (1976 June) (Folder 49: 12)
    - Kunferāns-i Hassan Nazih beh mināsbat-i yād bud-i Mosaddeq dar 14 Esfand, pamphlet, 1360 (1981) (Folder 49: 13)
    - Matn-i sukhanrānī beh minasbat: dahumīn sālmarg-i Khalīl Malakī, Doktor Amir Pishdad, (Tehran: s.n.), pamphlet, 1358 Tīr 20 (1979 July 11) (Folder 49: 14)
    - The Message of the Liberation Movement of Iran to the Leader of the Islamic Revolution of Iran Ayatollah Ruhallah Khomeini on Iran-Iraq War, (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), booklet, 1986 November (Folder 49: 15)
      See also Box 50, folder 5 for Persian translation
    - Mobārzāt-i sīyāsī va mobārzāt-i mazhabī, (Springfield, Mont.: Intishārat-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān Khārij az Kishvar), booklets, 1355 Farvardīn (1976 March) (Folder 49: 16)
    - Mosābeh-yi telefonī Mohandes Bazargan ba makhar ruznāmeh 'The Christian Monitor', (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), booklet, 1364 (1985) (Folder 49: 17)
    - Mudafā'at: dar dādgāh-i gayr-i sālih-i taqdīd-i nazar-i nizāmī, Mohandes Mehdi Bazargan (Tehran: Intishārat-i Mudarris), monograph, 1351 (1972) (Folder 50: 1)
    - Muvāzah-yi Nahzat dar kungreh'hā-yi sivvum, chehārum, va panjum, (Tehran: Nahzat-i Āzādi-i Īrān), chāp-i avval, booklet, 1362 (1983) (Folder 50: 2)
    - Pāsukh-i Mohandes Bāzārgān beh Ayatollāh Khāz'ali, (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), booklet, 1364 (1985) (Folder 50: 3)
    - Pāsukh-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān beh mutālib-i ruznāmeh-yi 'Kayhān' va 'Jomhourī Islāmī', (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), booklets, 1364 Mehr (1985 September) (Folder 50: 4)
    - Payām-i Nahzat-i Āzādī beh rahbar-i inqilāb-i islāmī-i īrān, (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), booklet, 1365 Shahrivar (1986 August) (Folder 50: 5)
      See also Box 49, folder 15 for English translation
    - Raz-i bilīun dular, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān), booklet, 1353 Shahrivar (1974 August) (Folder 50: 6)
    - Rīsheh gorāni'hā va mas'ul-i giriftārī'hā, booklet, 1366 Mordād (1987 July) (Folder 50: 7)
    - Sargozasht va sarnivisht-i idiuluzhī-yi inqilāb-i islāmī īrān, (Houston, Tex.: Maktab), booklets, 1364 (1985) (Folder 50: 8)
    - Shurashgarī va zadd shurashgarī, Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īran, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), booklet, 1353 Khordād 10 (1974 May 31) (Folder 50: 9)
    - Sukhānī chand dar bāreh-yi āncheh dar īrān rukh dād, chāp-i 2, booklet, 1358 (1979) (Folder 50: 10)
    - Tahlīlī dar bāreh-yi: Bāzārgāni khārijī, (S.l.: Hosseinī), booklet, 1361 Tīr (1982 June) (Folder 50: 11)
    - Yādnāmeh-yi bistumīn sālgard-i Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān, (Tehran: Nahzat-i Āzādī-i Īrān), chāp-i 3, 1362 (1983) (Folder 50: 12)
    - Zindigīnāmeh va mudaf'at-i mujāhid shahīd Mohammad Mofidī, (Springfield, Mont.: Intishārat-i Nahzat-i Āzādī Khārij az Kishvar), booklets, 1354 Day (1975 December) (Folder 50: 13)
    - Zindigīnāmeh va mudaf'at-i mujāhid shahīd Sa'īd Mohsin, (Bellville, Ill.: Intishārat-i Nahzat-i Āzādī Khārij az Kishvar), booklets, 1355 Shahrivar-1356 Khordād (1976 August-1977 May). (Folder 50: 14)
      Includes full English translation
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1362-1367 (1983-1988) (Folder 50: 15-18)
- Jabhah-i Millī, 1970-1988, undated; 51-52, 84 (Box 51-52, 84)
  - Serials (Folder 51, 84)
    - Īrān āzad, shumārah-i 76-78, 88; 16 va 46, urgān-i Jabhah-i Millī (Khārij az Kishvar), newspapers, 1349 Bahman-1365 Shahrivar (1971 January-1986 September) (Folder 51: 1-2)
    - Ittihād-i Buzurg, haftahnāmeh-yi Jabhah-i Millī Īrān dar rāh-i ittihād-i buzurg, shumārah-i 29, newspaper, 1358 Shahrivar (1979 August) (Folder 84: 2)
      Newspaper continues as Jabhah. See also Box 51, folders 3-8
    - Jabhah, sāl-i 1, 3-6, shumārah-i 8-11, 76, 80, 86, 96-108, (London: Jabhah-i Millī), newspapers, 1360 Āzar-1367 Khordād (1981 December-1988 July) (Folder 51: 3-8)
    - Jabhah-i Millī Īrān, shumārah-i 100 va 103, newspapers, 1357 Esfand (1978 February) (Folder 84: 2)
    - Khabar nāmeh-yi Jabhah-i Millī Īrān, shumārah-i 3, 9-10, 12-13, journals and newsletter, 1356 Āzar-1357 Mehr 17 (1977 November-1978 October 9) (Folder 51: 9-11)
    - Payām-i Jabhah-i Millī, shumārah-i 2, 6, 10, (Paris: Front National Iranien), newspapers, 1360 Ābān 5, Day 10, Esfand 28 (1981 October 27, December 31; 1982 March 18) (Folder 51: 12)
  - Monographs, booklets, and pamphlets (Folder 51-52)
    - Az Rizā Khān tā Rizā Shāh: taqīqī dar bāreh-i sālhā-yi 1299-1304 Shamsī, Farhang Qassemi (Köln, West Germany: I.N.F.), booklet, 1366 Farvardīn (1987 March) (Folder 51: 13)
      Copy signed by Farhang Qassemi
    - Fuhrsat-i kitāb-i mujud-i Jabhah-i Millīon-i Īrān, (London: s.n.), booklet, 1364 (1985) (Folder 51: 14)
    - Khātirat-i yik chirīkī dar zindān, Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, 1352 Mordād (1973 July) (Folder 51: 15)
    - Majmu'āh-yi az natiq'hā-yi tārikhi-i Duktur Mosaddeq, (S.l.: Īrān āzād), booklet, 1346 Esfand (1967 February) (Folder 51: 16)
      Added title in English, "A Collection of Mosaddeq's Historical Speeches"
    - Pīrāmun-i taghīr muzu'h idīuluzhīk-i Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), booklets, 1976 November (Folder 51: 17)
    - Ramz nivīsī, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), booklet, probably 1350s (1970s) (Folder 51: 18)
      Instructional manual, with examples and illustrations, for cryptic writing
    - Tahlīlī az sharāyat-i jām'eh-yi īrān, Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān'hā-yi Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, 1350 Āzar (1971 November) (Folder 51: 19)
    - Tahlīlī az sharāyat-i jām'eh-yi īrān: mobārzeh mussalhāneh ham istrātizhī, ham tāktīkī, Massoud Ahmadzadeh (S.l.: Intishārat-i Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, 1354 (1975) (Folder 52: 1)
      Originally published by the People's Fada'i-i Guerrillas of Iran
    - Tupāmāru'hā: tajribat-i jang-i chirīkī shurī dar Uruguay, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān'hā-yi Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), booklet, 1352 (1973) (Folder 52: 2)
    - Zadd shurash va jang-i inqilābī, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān'hā-yi Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, undated (Folder 52: 3)
    - Zindigī va mobārzeh Hu Shī Mīn, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān'hā-yi Jabhah-i Millī Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, 1352 Mehr (1973 November) (Folder 52: 4)
      Origially published in English in 1972 by the Foreign Languages Publishing House, Hanoi
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1350-1359 (1971-1980) (Folder 52: 5)
- Rāh-i Kārgar, 1979-1988, undated; 52-54 (Box 52-54: 5)
  Arranged in two groups: Serials and Booklets and pamphlets
  - Serials (Folder 52-53)
    - Fāshism, shumārah-i 1-5, journals, 1358 Ābān-Āzar (1979 October-November) (Folder 52: 6-7)
    - Khabarnāmeh, shumārah-i 1-3, journals, 1362 (1984) (Folder 52: 8)
    - Payām-i kārgar, shumārah-i 1-4, 8, journals, 1362 Ordibihisht-Day (1983 April-December) (Folder 52: 9-10)
    - Payām-i sorkh, shumārah-i 7-8, (Berlin: Rāh-i Kārgar Khārij az Kishvar), journals, 1362 Shahrivar-Mehr (1983 August-September) (Folder 52: 11)
    - Payk-i kārgarān, shumārah-i 2, (Berlin: s.n.), journal, 1362 Bahman (1983 January) (Folder 52: 12)
    - Rāh-i kārgar, dawreh-yi 2, sāl-i 4-6, shumārah-i 1-5, 11, newspapers, 1363 Farvardīn-Bahman (1984 March-1985 January) (Folder 53: 1-2)
    - Rāh-i kārgar (t'urik), shumārah-i 1, 4, 6, 1362 Shahrivar-1367 Mordād (1983 August-1988 July) (Folder 53: 3-4)
    - Rīgāi kārīkār, Sāzmān-i Kārgarān Inqilābī-i Īrān (Rāh-i Kārgar) Kumiteh-yi Kurdistān, sāl-i avval, shumārah-i 3-4, 8-9, booklets, 1362 Ābān-1363 Ordibihisht (1983 October-1984 April) (Folder 53: 5-6)
  - Booklets and pamphlets (Folder 53)
    - Dar barābar-i rivizīunīsm vatuz-i susīāl impirīālīsm, (Berlin: Rāh-i Kārgar Khārij az Kishvar), booklet, undated (Folder 53: 7)
    - Internāsīyunālīsm-i prulitārī (dar t'urī va 'āmal), (Berlin: Rāh-i Kārgar), booklet, 1361 Āzar (1982 December) (Folder 53: 8)
    - Mitāduluzhī-yi marhāleh-yi inqilāb, (Berlin: Rāh-i Kārgar Khārij az Kishvar), booklet, 1361 Ābān (1982 November) (Folder 53: 9)
    - Miscellaneous booklets and pamphlets, 1358-1361 (1979-1982) (Folder 53: 9-10)
      Includes printed matter published by supporters of Rāh-i Kārgar on the theory of revoultion
- Sāzmān-i Vahdat Kumunīstī, 1977-1986, undated; 54-55 (Box 54-55: 9-10)
  - Serials (Folder 54)
    - Andīsheh-yi Rahā'i, shumārah-i 2-4, 6, (Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland: Khārij az Kishvar Sāzmān-i Vahdat Kumunīstī), journals, 1363 Mehr-1365 Esfand (1983 September-1986 March) (Folder 54: 1-3)
    - Navīd Rahā'i, shumārah-i 6, newsletter, 1362 Mehr (1983 September) (Folder 54: 4)
    - Rahā'i, newsletters and journals, 1358-1365 (1979-1986) (Folder 54: 5-9)
      - Irān, shumārah-i 4, 69, 110, 1358 Farvardīn-1360 Day (1979 March-1981 December) (Folder 54: 5)
      - Chicago, Ill. (English), nos. 1-2, 4, 1981 January-1982 (Folder 54: 6)
      - Chicago, Ill. (Persian), dawreh-yi 3, shumārah-i 2-3, 1361 Esfand-1362 Tir (1983 March-May) (Folder 54: 7)
      - Sunndyberg, Sweden, sāl-i 2, shumārah-i 57 va dawreh-yi 3, shumārah-i 1-2 va 11, 1359 Āzar-1365 (1980 October-1986) (Folder 54: 8-9)
    - Rahā'i-i zan, sāl-i avval, shumārah-i 10, journal photocopy, 1358 Bahman (1979 January) (Folder 54: 10)
    - Miscellaneous serials published in Sweden, 1362-1363 (1983-1984) (Folder 54: 11)
  - Monographs and booklets (Folder 54-55)
    - Bahsī pīrāmun-i t'urī-i inqilāb, (Sweden: Havādārān-i Sāzmān-i Vahdat Kumunistī dar Su'id), booklets, 1359 (1980) (Folder 54: 12)
    - Cheh nabāyad kard?, Guruh-i Ittihād-i Kumunīst, (S.l.: s.n.), monograph, 1356 Bahman (1977 January) (Folder 54: 13)
    - Mobārzāt tabaqātī dar Luhristan, Havādārān-i Sāzmān-i Vahdat Kumunīstī dar Amrikā, monograph, undated (Folder 54: 14)
    - 'Namunah'i zībā' az bih maslakh kashanīdan-i chap, Havādārān-i Sāzmān-i Vahdat Kumunīstī dar Urupā, booklet, 1360 (1981) (Folder 54: 15)
    - Naqdī bar nazrat-i sāzmān-i paykār, booklet, 1982 October (Folder 55: 1)
    - "Tirutskism: saqat-i dīālīktīkī-i Linīnī," az Mārksism ya Tirutskism, 1358 Esfand (1979 March) (Folder 55: 2)
    - General booklets on revolution and imperialism, 1359-1361 (1970-1982) (Folder 55: 3)
- Ittihād-i Mubārizān-i Kumunīst, 1979-1984, undated; 55-56
  - Serials (Folder 55)
    - Bi-su-yi susīālīsm, urgān-i t'urīk-sīyāsī-i ittihād-i mubārizān-i kumunīst, journals, 1359-1363 (1980-1984), undated (Folder 55)
      - Zamīmeh-i 2, shumārah-i 4, 1360 (1981) (Folder 55: 4)
      - Shumārah-i 5-6, 1361 Bahman-1362 Mordād (1982 January-1983 July) (Folder 55: 5)
      - Dawreh-yi 2, shumārah-i 1, 1363 Shahrivar (1984 August) (Folder 55: 6)
      - Excerpts from nos. 1-4, 1359 (1980), undated (Folder 55: 7-9)
        In Persian
    - Kārgar-i Kumunīst, shumārah-i 7 va 9, journals, 1362 Ordibihist-Tīr (1983 April and June) (Folder 55: 10)
  - Booklets (Folder 55-56)
    - Durnamāi falākat va 'atlāi-i novīn inqilāb, chāp-i 2, booklet, 1359 Bahman (1980 January) (Folder 55: 11)